Finding aid for Lon G. Nungesser Hope for Humanity Papers, 1970-1989
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center)
Lon G. Nungesser Hope for Humanity Papers 1970-1989
Nungesser, Lon G.
2 Linear Feet
ams0099
The Lon G. Nungesser Hope for Humanity Papers, 1970-1989 comprise correspondence, drafts of unpublished and published manuscripts, ideas for research projects, family history material, publishers' contracts, placement files, and copies of his three books: Homosexual acts, actors and identities (Praeger, 1983), Epidemic of courage: facing AIDS in America (St. Martin's, 1986), and Notes on living until we say goodbye: a personal guide (St. Martin's, 1988). The papers reflect Nungesser's struggle against homophobia and particularly his battle with AIDS and coping with terminal illness. Correspondents include Dana H. Bramel, Stuart Kellogg, and Philip G. Zimbardo.
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center) Joseph A. Labadie Collection
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Papers were donated by Lon Nungesser in 1988 and 1989.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Original audio cassettes have been digitized and the digital surrogates are available for researcher use in the Special Collections Reading Room.
Lonnie Gene Nungesser was born in Springfield, Mo., on May 30, 1953, to a family living below the poverty level in the Ozark Mountains. He left home at the age of fifteen, graduated from Mountain Grove (Mo.) High School in 1971, and entered the U. S. Coast Guard, serving until 1973. He was licensed as a Southern Baptist minister in 1969. In 1975 he received his Associate's Degree from the College of Alameda (Ca.), where the previous year he had been elected the first Caucasian student body president. In 1979 Lon earned a B.A. in psychology from Stanford University and, in 1982, an M.A. in social psychology from the State University of New York at Stony Brook.
Lon left Stony Brook in early 1983 because of faltering health. In October of that year he was diagnosed as having Kaposi's Sarcoma and AIDS (Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome) and told he had only a few months to live. Since his diagnosis, Lon has dedicated his life to helping others survive the experiences he has lived through - coping with terminal disease and homophobia. To that end, Lon has written extensively. In addition to several unpublished works, he has three books: Homosexual Acts, Actors and Identities (Praeger, 1983); Epidemic of Courage: Facing AIDS in America (St. Martin's, 1986); and Notes on Living until We Say Goodbye: A Personal Guide (St. Martin's, 1988).
Although there is some memorabilia from his high school years and some personal mementoes, the bulk of this collection reflects Nungesser's struggle against homophobia, and particularly his battle with AIDS. The papers include published and unpublished writings, contracts with publishers, book reviews, drafts of research projects and grant proposals, correspondence, college placement files, articles and interviews, photographs, and clippings. There are two videocassettes, one of a call-in talk show with Nungesser as guest, and the other of Nungesser reading from Notes on Living until We Say Goodbye. In addition, there are two audio cassettes of radio interviews of Nungesser. The 1984 interview concerns Homosexual Acts, Actors and Identities and the 1988 interview discusses his battle with AIDS and Notes on Living until We Say Goodbye. These audio cassettes have been reformatted.
Nungesser is a prolific writer. There are several unpublished, book-length manuscripts in the papers, as well as dissertation and grant proposals and other writings. All relate to the social psychology of homosexuals, and several concern AIDS. Copies of Nungesser's three books have been cataloged for the Labadie Collection.
In April 1989, Lon began sending his correspondence and writings to the Department of Rare Books and Special Collections on computer disks. The files on these disks have been printed and those that did not duplicate materials already in the collection were interfiled. The disks are stored separately from the collection (in Case 2). Each of the printed files are labeled with the name of the file and its date of creation.
The papers have been divided into five series.
Genre Terms:
Contracts; Manuscripts; Photographs
Subjects:
Alfred, Randy.; Bell, Alan P., 1932-.; Bem, Sandra L.; Boyer, Cherrie.; Bramel, Dana H., 1935-.; Bullock, William D. (William David).; Calder, Daniel Gillmore.; De Cecco, John P.; Denneny, Michael.; Garfield, Sol L. (Sol Louis), 1918-.; Jones, Dezie Dell, 1941-.; Kalish, Harry I.; Kellogg, Stuart.; Koop, C. Everett (Charles Everett), 1916-.; Lewis, Robert A. (Robert Alan), 1932-.; Masters, William H.; Minton, Henry L.; Morin, Stephen F.; Morrison, H.W.; Rodgers, Lee.; Selvin, Johnnie Barnes.; Stark, Fortney H.; Zimbardo, Philip G.; AIDS (Disease).; Homosexuality -- Psychological aspects.; Gays.; Social Psychology.
- Series I: Personal/Biographical
  Series I. Personal/Biographical comprises Nungesser's statement of purpose for creating the collection, materials relating to his high school and college education, an unfinished family history project, a journal he began keeping in 1988 (parts of which are duplicated in the outgoing correspondence files), and an article about him and his Epidemic of Courage that appeared in Stony Brook magazine. There are several photograph and memorabilia albums containing recent and childhood photos of Lon, photos of his family, Bill Bullock, and places of significance to Lon, as well as his birth certificate, diplomas, clippings, greeting cards, etc. There is one restricted folder: Placement files and resume, 1975-86.
  - The Nungesser Papers: Hope for Humanity. Statement of purpose, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Bible (Box 1, Box 2)
  - Mountain Grove High School, Mountain Grove, MO
    - 1970 yearbook (Box 1, Box 3)
    - 1971 yearbook (Box 1, Box 4)
    - 1971 memorabilia book (Box 1, Box 5)
  - College of Alameda, 1974-75 (Box 1, Box 6)
  - Who's Who among Students in American Vocational and Technical Schools, 1974-75 (Box 1, Box 7)
  - Stanford University
    - Application for admission/senior honors program 1974 (Box 1, Box 8)
    - Graduation program, 1979 (Box 1, Box 9)
    - Graduation photo (Box 1, Box 10)
  - University of California - Berkeley. Statement of purpose for application to graduate school, 1979 (Box 1, Box 11)
  - SUNY - Stony Brook
    - General, 1982-84 (Box 1, Box 12)
    - "Psychology of Sex Roles." Course proposal outline, 1981 (Box 1, Box 13)
  - Pacific Graduate School of Psychology. Admission application, 1986 (Box 1, Box 14)
  - Placement files and resume, 1975-86 (Box 1, Box 15)
  - Resumes, (Lon & Bill) 1986 (Box 1, Box 16)
  - Nungesser family history project (Box 1, Box 17)
  - Personal journal, 1988 (Box 1, Box 18)
  - Notes to executor, (Lon & Bill) 1988 (Box 1, Box 19)
  - Tenant and personal information, (Lon & Bill) 1988 (Box 1, Box 20)
  - Health management charts, (Lon & Bill) 1988 (Box 1, Box 21)
  - Record of difficulty with landlord, John Renbourne, 1988 (Box 1, Box 22)
  - Statements re beating of Nov. 30, 1988 (Box 1, Box 23)
  - Photo/Memorabilia albums
    - #1 "The early years with Bill" (Box 1, Box 24-25)
    - #2 "More cherished moments with Bill" (Box 1, Box 26-27)
    - #3 [greeting cards] (Box 1, Box 28-29)
    - #4 [greeting cards] (Box 2, Box 1-2)
    - #5 "The life and times of Lonnie Gene Nungesser" (Box 2, Box 3-5)
  - Ireland, Kevin. "An epidemic of courage: AIDS patient Lon Nungesser helps others confront an irrational killer," Stony Brook, vol. 1 #1, Spring 1987 (Box 2, Box 6)
- Series II: Correspondence
  Series II, Correspondence consists of outgoing correspondence, arranged chronologically, and incoming correspondence arranged alphabetically. Tora K. Bikson, Michael Denneny, Christine Friedlander, Stuart Kellogg, Gustav Neumann, and Philip G. Zimbardo are the most extensively represented correspondents.
  - Outgoing, 1978-87 (Box 2, Box 7)
  - 1988 (Box 2, Box 8)
  - 1989 (Box 2, Box 9)
  - Outgoing correspondence, Bill's (Box 2, Box 10)
  - Incoming, A - C (Box 2, Box 11)
  - D - F (Box 2, Box 12)
  - G - K (Box 2, Box 13)
  - Kellogg, Stuart (Box 2, Box 14)
  - L - M (Box 2, Box 15)
  - N - S (Box 2, Box 16)
  - T - Z (Box 16, Box 2, Box 17)
  - unidentified (Box 2, Box 18)
  - Mailing list, Nov. 1988 (Box 2, Box 19)
- Series III: Writings
  Series III. Writings contains published and unpublished works from 1977 to 1989 arranged alphabetically by title. Include copies of Nungesser's three books: Homosexual Acts, Actors and Identities, Epidemic of Courage: Facing AIDS in America, and Notes on Living until We Say Goodbye: A Personal Guide, as well as reviews and clippings about the books. Nungesser's unpublished writings cover a variety of topics, including homophobia, coping with terminal illness (particularly AIDS) and the associated stigma, and ethics in the medical profession. They vary in format from poetry and short articles to book-length manuscripts and grant proposals.
  - AIDS Survey questionnaire, 1986 (Box 2, Box 20)
  - "AIDS for AIDS: Actively Infused Daily Strategies for Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome," 1986 (Box 2, Box 21)
  - "Armistead Maupin Talks about AIDS," Playguy, Interview by LN June 1985 (Box 2, Box 22)
  - "Can Homophobia Be Cured?" In Men in Difficult Times, ed. by Robert A. Lewis. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice-Hall, Essay by LN c1981. (Box 2, Box 23)
  - "Career Decision Making," 1981 (Box 2, Box 24)
  - "Dimensions of Human Response: Cognitive, Motivational and Emotional Responses to the Human Dilemma of AIDS," [1984] (Box 2, Box 25)
  - Epidemic of Courage: Facing AIDS in America. New York: St. Martin's Press, c1986 (Box 2, Box 26)
    - Reviews and clippings (Box 2, Box 27)
  - Epidemic of Courage... German trans. Der Wille zu Leben: AIDS-Betroffene berichten ber ihre K mpfe und Erfolge, 1986 (Box 2, Box 28)
  - "The Experiences and Expressions of Gay Males with AIDS," 1984 (Box 2, Box 29)
  - Heroes, Hopes, and Heartbreaks: Selected Conversations about AIDS, 1985
    - chapters 1-6 (Box 2, Box 30)
    - chapters 7-12 (Box 2, Box 31)
    - chapters 13-14 (Box 2, Box 32)
  - "Homophobic Prejudice and Speech Disruptions," 1977 (Box 2, Box 33)
  - "Homophobic Prejudice in Homosexual Males," Senior honors thesis, Stanford 1979. (Box 2, Box 34)
  - Homosexual Acts, Actors and Identities. New York: Praeger, c1983 (Box 3, Box 1)
    - Reviews and clippings (Box 3, Box 2)
  - "How to Read and Understand Your Own Blood Tests," 1989 (Box 3)
  - "The Lesbian Mother as a Role Model: A Case Study and Discussion," Co-authored by Stephanie Erickson 1977. (Box 3, Box 4)
  - "Life's Discoveries after a Life-Threatening Diagnosis: A Crash Course in Survival," Video script 1988. (Box 3, Box 5)
  - "Life's Discoveries after a Life-Threatening Diagnosis: A Psychology Today Audio Series," 1988 (Box 3, Box 6)
  - "Men and Emotion: An Annotated Bibliography," [1981] (Box 3, Box 7)
  - "A New Cognitive-Behavioral Program for Coping with AIDS," AmFAR grant application 1986. (Box 3, Box 8)
  - "A New Cognitive-Behavioral Program for Coping with Human Immunodeficiency Virus," 1986-87 (Box 3, Box 9)
  - Nightmare in Gay America: The Social and Psychological Aspects of AIDS, 1985
    - chapters 1-4 (Box 3, Box 10)
    - chapters 5-8 (Box 3, Box 11)
    - chapters 9-10, bibliography (Box 3, Box 12)
  - Notes on Living until We Say Goodbye: A Personal Guide. New York: St. Martin's Press, c1988
    - Hard cover copy (Box 3, Box 13)
    - Paperback edition (Box 3, Box 14)
    - Draft (Box 3, Box 15)
    - Excerpts (Box 3, Box 16)
    - "An Author's Reading in Three Parts," 1988 (Box 3, Box 17)
    - Quoted in a sermon by Richard Inlander, 1988 (Box 3, Box 18)
    - Reviews and clippings (Box 3, Box 19)
    - New preface, 1988 (Box 3, Box 20)
  - "Now We Need Men's Lib," 1981 (Box 3, Box 21)
  - Nungesser Homosexual Attitudes Inventory, 1979 (Box 3, Box 22)
  - "Nungesser's Health Psychology Coping Plan," 1988 (Box 3, Box 23)
  - "Perceived Sense of Social Stigma and Reactions to AIDS," 1986, 1988 (Box 3, Box 24)
  - "Personal Health Ethics," 1988 (Box 3, Box 25)
  - Poetry (Box 3, Box 26)
  - Positive Memory Study, Proposal, consent form, requests for volunteers 1988-89. (Box 3, Box 27)
  - "Prime Time Portraits: Tales of Personal Quests toward Positive Memories," 1988 (Box 3, Box 28)
  - "Quality of Life and Chronic Illness," Dissertation proposal, SUNY 1985. (Box 3, Box 29)
  - "Reports from the Front Line: Fighting the Battle against AIDS," 1989 (Box 3, Box 30)
  - "Social Stigma and Self-efficacy: A Study of the Relationship between Attitude Dimensions that Influcence Health-Promoting Behavior, and the Quality of Life among Men with AIDS," 1986 (Box 3, Box 31)
  - "Social Stigma and Self-efficacy: A Study of the Relationship between Attitude Dimensions that Influence Health-Promoting Behavior, and the Quality of Life among Men with Human Immunodeficiency Virus," Dissertation proposal, SUNY 1987. (Box 3, Box 32)
  - Spectrum of Life: Reflections of a Man Facing a Fatal Diagnosis, 1987
    - chapters 1-7 (Box 3, Box 33)
    - chapters 8-9, bibliography (Box 3, Box 34)
  - "Still Alive: A Crash Course in Survival," Script written for film 1988. (Box 3, Box 35)
  - "Survival Tactics: A Personal Manual for Managing the Mortal Condition," 1986 (Box 3, Box 36)
  - "Survival Tactics for Terminal Illness: Managing the Mortal Condition," 1987 (Box 3, Box 37)
  - "Theoretical Bases for Research on the Acquisition of Social-Sex Roles by Children of Lesbian Mothers," Journal of Homosexuality, vol. 5 #3, Spring 1980 (Box 4, Box 1)
  - "Today's Teenagers: A Needs Assessment and Feasibility Study of Programs and Services for Palo Alto Area Adolescents," 1978 (Box 4, Box 2)
  - "Trends and Issues in the Study of Homophobia," 1981 (Box 4, Box 3)
  - Consent forms from interviewees for Nightmare in Gay America and Epidemic of Courage (Box 4)
  - Contracts with publishers (Box 4, Box 5)
  - Research and writings ideas - notes (Box 4, Box 6)
- Series IV: Personal Appearances/Speeches
  Series IV, Personal Appearances/Speeches is comprised of typescripts, clippings, videocassettes, and audiocassettes of speeches and interviews of Lon between 1979 and 1988.
  - Gay Blue Jeans Day speech, May 1979 (Box 4, Box 7)
  - Gay Life radio interview (KSAN), (cassette tape) (HOPEAUD-001) Feb. 26, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Johnnie Selvin Show, (videotape) 1984 (Box 4, Box 9)
  - "The Resurrection of Inspiration," Outline for sermon Mar. 30, 1986 (Box 4, Box 10)
  - "Notes on Living" reading for Dept. of Psychology, Stanford University, (videotape) Mar. 19, 1988 (Box 4, Box 11)
  - Lee Rodgers Show (KGO), (cassette tape) (HOPEAUD-002) Apr. 29, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Lee Rodgers Show - Side A
    - Lee Rodgers Show - Side B
- Series V: Subject Files
  Series V: Suubject Files, consists of several folders of materials on a variety of topics, including several issues of AIDS Treatment News, a bibliography of sources dealing with the psychology of coping with illness, and samples of resumes Lon created for other people. Also includes a file entitled "RAM: Reforming American Medicine--Defending the Right to Self-Knowledge" which contains articles about ethics in the medical profession, newsletters and fact sheets from Project Inform (San Francisco), and a short information sheet created by Nungesser.
  - "AIDS Treatment News," 1988-89 (Box 4, Box 13)
  - Contact sheet, 1989 (Box 4, Box 14)
  - Crisis referrals, n.d. (Box 4, Box 15)
  - Game - "Jumping Perspectives" (Box 4, Box 16)
  - Kabalarian Philosophy name analysis (Box 4, Box 17)
  - RAM: Reforming American Medicine, 1989 (Box 4, Box 18)
  - Resources, 1989 (Box 4, Box 19)
  - Resume samples (Box 4, Box 20)
  - Clippings (Box 4, Box 21)
- Subject Files
  (Nungesser accretion from Lois Smith, 3-11-94)
  - Arcadia, Ltd. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Ethics and health (Box 5)
  - Food bank (Box 5)
  - HarperCollins Publishers (Box 5)
  - HIPP [i.e., Health Insurance Premium Payment] (Box 5)
  - Holocaust survivors... (Box 5)
  - Hom, Fred (Box 5)
  - Homobigotry (Box 5)
  - IBS Press (Box 5)
  - Ketwig, Ken (Box 5)
  - Medical records (ring binder and loose sheets) (Box 5)
  - Peer-Counseling (Box 5)
  - Photos (Box 5)
  - Publicity pack (Box 5)
  - Receipts and 19911992 (Box 5)
  - Resume-personal (Box 5)
  - Siegel, Bernie (Box 5)
  - Social stigma and self-efficacy (Box 5)
  - Transcripts (Box 5)
- Writings-typescripts
  - Axioms for caregivers, 1991. (Box 5)
  - Cross-disability and AIDS: a peer support training manual, 1991. (Box 5)
  - Notes from a man with AIDS. (Box 5)
  - Book:Der Wille zu Leben, c1986 (German translation of Epidemic of Courage). (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous papers, 1 box, unsorted
  - Audio cassettes access copies, 7 items (Box 5)
    Reformatted use copies of original audio casettes. Originals have been restricted for preservation purposes.
  - Video cassettes, 10 items (Box 5)
  - Computer disks, 25 5.25 in. disks (Box 5)
  - Original audio cassettes
    Contains original audio cassettes.
    Original audio cassettes have been restricted for preservation purposes. CD access copies are located in Box 5.
    - KGO 29 April 1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - KSAN Gay Life 26 February 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Photo Albums
  - Photo Album One: The Early Years with Bill
    - Lon at "Duck Pond" in E. Setauket, N.Y., moments before leaving for CA, March, 1983. (Volume 1, Page 1)
      (Top)
    - Bill after helping Lon pack to leave for CA. (Volume 1, Page 1)
      (Bottom)
    - Lon's Holy Vows to Bill (Volume 1, Page 2)
      Full (Full page)
    - Bill's Holy Vows to Lon photo of Bill when we met (Volume 1, Page 3)
    - Lon near Bodega Bay, 1983 (Volume 1, Page 4)
    - Bill overlooking Pacific Ocean, Spring, 1983 (Volume 1, Page 4)
    - Lon near Bodega Bay, 1983 (Volume 1, Page 5)
    - Bill in front of California wild flowers of Sonoma, California (Volume 1, Page 5)
      (Middle)
    - Bill sitting on his first car, May, 1983 (Volume 1, Page 5)
    - Lon & Bill at a pool party, Summer of 1983 (Volume 1, Page 6)
    - Bill posing at pool-side (Volume 1, Volume 6)
    - Bill explaining the dive he is about to perform (Volume 1, Page 7)
    - Bill in the tuck and roll position - it was a perfect dive! (Volume 1, Page 7)
    - Bill & Lon "The Happy Couple." (Volume 1, Page 8)
      (Center)
    - Bill and Lon in 1984 (Volume 1, Page 9)
    - Bill with his two cats (Volume 1, Page 10)
    - Mission Dolores Park (Volume 1, Page 10)
    - Lon in Mission Dolores (Volume 1, Page 11)
    - Bill strikes a pose! (Volume 1, Page 11)
    - Bill in front of fire place at our home in Redwood City, California (Volume 1, Page 12)
    - Bill playing flute for an elderly woman at her home, 1985 (Volume 1, Page 12)
    - Lon kicks back with fond company, 1985 (Volume 1, Page 13)
    - Bill in Bobby Reynold's and Mark Wood's home on Valentine Day, 1984 (Volume 1, Page 14)
    - Jasmine on sofa (Volume 1, Page 15)
    - Jasmine about to attack the camera! (Volume 1, Page 15)
    - View from Sonoma mtn. (Volume 1, Page 16)
    - Sabrina, Jasmine's sister (Volume 1, Page 16)
    - Jasmine when she's tired of the flash (Volume 1, Page 17)
    - Jasmine stalking for mice (Volume 1, Page 17)
    - A Petunia bed we planted (Volume 1, Page 18)
    - Squash bed in garden, with beans and a Nasturtium boarder (Volume 1, Page 18)
    - Our tomato patch (Volume 1, Page 19)
    - A part of our flower bed (Volume 1, Page 19)
    - Jasmine looking for a bathroom in fresh dirt - ugh! (Volume 1, Page 20)
    - Sister's plotting a scheme to get under the mesh net in to the fresh bark of the strawberry bed. (Volume 1, Page 20)
    - Artichoke plant behind California Poppies (Volume 1, Page 21)
    - Strawberry patch: The first year (Volume 1, Page 21)
    - The start of a great corn and pole bean crop (Volume 1, Page 22)
    - My flowers galore! (Volume 1, Page 22)
    - Wild vine (Volume 1, Page 23)
    - Fall crop of broccoli, turnips and carrots (Volume 1, Page 23)
    - Sabrina won the dish! (Volume 1, Page 24)
    - Eggplant section (Volume 1, Page 24)
    - Jasmine's favorite position: The "please rub my tummy" position. (Volume 1, Page 24)
    - Sabrina in my Moss Rose bed - She was lucky I thought it was cute! (Volume 1, Page 25)
    - Fall colors show first on this berry bush (Volume 1, Page 25)
    - Flower bed in Fall (Volume 1, Page 25)
    - Sabrina showing off (Volume 1, Page 26)
    - It's pumpkin time! (Volume 1, Page 26)
    - Rows of radish (Volume 1, Page 26)
    - Lon a few days after AIDS diagnosis was confirmed (Volume 1, Page 27)
    - Bill in 1985 (Volume 1, Page 28)
    - Lon in 1985 (Volume 1, Page 29)
    - Bill in bedroom, 1985 (Volume 1, Page 30)
    - View of Golden Gate Bridge from North of Bridge (Volume 1, Page 31)
    - San Gregorio Beach (Volume 1, Page 31)
    - San Gregorio Beach (Volume 1, Page 32)
      (Top & Bottom)
    - San Gregorio Beach (Volume 1, Page 33)
    - San Gregorio Beach (Volume 1, Page 34)
    - Pond near Pacific coast (Volume 1, Page 34)
    - Pond near Pacific coast (Volume 1, Page 35)
    - Redwoods near Gurneville (Volume 1, Page 36)
    - Where the Russian River meets Pacific Ocean (Volume 1, Page 36)
    - Pacific coast at Ft. Ross (Volume 1, Page 37)
    - A tourist town in the Redwood forest North of S. F. 60 miles (Volume 1, Page 37)
    - The Russian River (Volume 1, Page 38)
    - Downtown Gurneville, CA (Volume 1, Page 39)
    - The Russian River (Volume 1, Page 39)
    - Going North to Napa (Volume 1, Page 40)
    - Bodega Bay (Volume 1, Page 40)
    - Going South on G.G. (Volume 1, Page 41)
    - Gigantic Redwoods along the Russian River (Volume 1, Page 41)
    - Another day at the Russian River (Volume 1, Page 42)
    - Another day of sun worship in the driftwood "beach condos" at San Gregorio (Volume 1, Page 42)
    - The driftwood shelters at San Gregorio (Volume 1, Page 43)
      Top &(Top & Bottom)
    - The first years garden (Volume 1, Page 44)
    - Sabrina giving Bill that "Don't you dare spray me!" look (Volume 1, Page 44)
    - Sabrina, the attack cat! (Volume 1, Page 45)
    - Our newly painted kitchen (Volume 1, Page 45)
    - The walkway to the garden (Volume 1, Page 46)
    - Bill & Lon in their piece of paradise (Volume 1, Page 47)
    - Lon 18 months after AIDS diagnosis (Volume 1, Page 47)
    - Lon & Bill after Joe (Lon's former lover) died of AIDS (Volume 1, Page 48)
    - Cats in the flower bed (Volume 1, Page 49)
    - Sabrina in my moss rose bed - again! (Volume 1, Page 50)
    - Lon & Bill (Volume 1, Page 51)
    - Lon & Bill (Volume 1, Page 52)
    - Lon & Bill (Volume 1, Page 53)
    - Lon & Bill, Christmas, 1984 (Volume 1, Page 54)
    - Lon & Bill exchange a Christmas Kiss, 1984 (Volume 1, Page 55)
    - Lon & Bill, Christmas, 1984 (Volume 1, Page 56)
    - Lon & Bill after Lon's visit to his Ozark Mountain home, June, 1985 (Volume 1, Page 57)
    - Winter at the beach, 1985 (Volume 1, Page 58)
    - Spring at the beach, 1986 (Volume 1, Page 59)
    - Lon answering questions about coping with AIDS from a person recently diagnosed with the virus (Volume 1, Page 60)
    - Jasmine imitating an Opossum (Volume 1, Page 61)
    - Lon going to work as the manager of a job placement agency, 1985 (Volume 1, Page 62)
    - Lon's desk at the placement and resume writing agency (Volume 1, Page 62)
    - Lon after receiving his first royalty check from Homosexual Acts, Actors and Identities, 1985 (Volume 1, Page 63)
    - The royalty check itself was less than 20.00, and the mountain backdrop represents the effort it took to write and place the manuscript (Volume 1, Page 63)
    - Bill after a gymnastics workout, 1985 (Volume 1, Page 64)